# son **Gomes**

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER · BA (COMPUTER SCIENCE) · BS (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY)

□ 732-675-1327 | ■ JasonG7234@gmail.com | ★ www.jasongomes.me | 🖸 JasonG7234 | 🛅 JasonGomes

## Summary \_\_\_\_\_

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

Driven software engineer with 3 years of experience in full-stack development. Experience with software development & testing, inter-team communication, and mentorship. Strengths in both Python and Java along with a consistent desire to keep learning in an ever-evolving field.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**iCIMS** Holmdel, New Jersey

- · Utilizes Java 8 principles to refactor existing code and provide new features for HR SaaS company
- Automates Selenium Webdriver tests in Java to simplify multiple tests down to a button click · Rectifies critical severity production code causing memory leaks and thread-locking with SQL
- · Creates test plans in TestRail and TM4J platforms to reduce released bugs and boost customer satisfaction
- Improves legacy front-end UI by creating and editing Single Page Applications with React and Redux
- · Provides enhanced API solutions to Amazon in order to meet growing GDPR requirements
- · Oversees and maintains Spring Boot microservices to reduce strain on Java monolith

**ShotQuality** Remote

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER Mar 2021 - PRESENT

- Develops Python Flask REST API endpoints related to profile creation and statistic gathering
- Functions as Linux server administrator, including automating a Bash script to create a daily server build
- Runs SQL on production database to query accounts, delete users, and edit permissions
- · Automates profile creation via Stripe webhook to save an hour of daily manual account registrations
- · Implemented entire ShotQuality testing framework using Python's pytest and React's jest modules

L'Oreal Berkeley Heights, New Jersey

HRIS ANALYST INTERN

- · Redesigned L'Oreal-wide HRIS homepage using Microsoft Sharepoint software and HTML elements
- Collaborated on L'Oreal Anywhere mobile app development with Capriza software
- · Created Windows batch files to automate manual data entry, file-moving, and internet navigation
- Wrote Visual Basic Excel macros to streamline weekly and quarterly file uploads

New Brunswick, New Jersey

Sep. 2015 - May. 2019

June. 2017 - August. 2017

Jun. 2018 - PRESENT

## Education

#### **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey**

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & B.S IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

• GPA: 3.66

• Extracurriculars: Undergraduate Student Alliance of Computer Scientists Mentor

Projects \_\_\_\_\_

**NBA Draft Model** Old Bridge, New Jersey

PYTHON WEB SCRAPER AND MACHINE LEARNING MODEL USED TO PREDICT UNDER-THE-RADAR NBA DRAFT PICKS

Nov. 2019

- Utilizes BeautifulSoup to parse websites and identify relevant statistics
- Organizes stats and CSV files with pandas and numpy to allow for easy data manipulation
- Graphs scatter plots and line graphs using matplotlib to visualize the data
- Creates a tensorflow neural network and a logistic regression model & a gradient boosting model with ML library sklearn for data analysis

Skills\_\_\_\_\_

Languages Java, Python, React, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bash, NodeJS

**Frameworks** Flask, Hibernate, Redux, Spring Boot

Tools Atlassian Suite, AWS, Figma, Git, Jenkins, JMeter, NVDA, TM4J **Soft Skills** Agile Methodologies, Mentorship, Teamwork, Project Management

**Hobbies** Basketball, Chess, Fantasy Football, Tinkering